Hi. This is Michelle with Intentional Travelers
and in this video I’ll be sharing why we started
using SafetyWing for travel medical insurance
and some important things to know about it.
Jedd and I consider ourselves to be
pretty healthy and though we travel often,
we don’t tend to do high risk sports or bungee
jumping or things like that. For a long time,
we only traveled with a very basic medical
evacuation insurance, but once the pandemic hit,
we felt some risks associated with
travel had increased - not just for
our health but the likelihood of logistical
interruptions, delayed flights, lost luggage,
etc. - it all compounded and that motivated
us to be more prepared just in case.
One thing I appreciate most about SafetyWing
is they accommodate long-term travel really
well. That said, you don’t have to travel the
way we do to benefit from their insurance. We
like that SafetyWing is flexible, affordable,
and offers the coverage that most travelers need.
So what is SafetyWing Nomad
Insurance and what does it cover?
It covers you anywhere outside your home country,
with the exception of sanctioned countries like
North Korea. It covers unexpected illness or
injury abroad as well as emergency travel benefits
like unplanned overnight stays, evacuation in
the case of local unrest, and lost luggage, etc.
When people started getting stuck
in other countries due to Covid,
a lot of insurance providers would not cover
anything Covid-related. But SafetyWing does - they
cover treatment and tests for Covid that are
medically necessary, just like any other illness
you might get after you start traveling.
We’ve been lucky so far, but you never
know when you might twist your ankle,
or worse, and it gives peace of mind to
have travel insurance so those worst case
scenarios won’t empty your bank account.
Pricing for SafetyWing insurance is based
solely on your age and whether you’ll be in
the US or not. You can get a free quote for
your trip through the link below this video
or learn more about what’s covered and how
it works in the detailed review on our blog.